Ankit Singh Kushwah

C++ Game Programmer

HORSHAM,UK

I am a passionate software engineer with 5+ years of experience in the games industry. I am looking for opportunities where team is pushing technical boundaries, creating fresh gameplay experiences and where I get to tackle problems which really challenge me to push my technical & creative knowledge. I want to make games fun.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

C++ Gameplay Programmer | Unannounced AAA Game | CREATIVE ASSEMBLY | UK

2022 - Present

- Implemented reinforcement system & different spawners
- Implemented various ability behaviours
- Implemented stats/attribute modification system & tag system
- Implemented movement orders/behaviours : Jumping, Tactical Retreating & Teleportation
- Implemented damage rules for array of different interactions : Melee, Range, AoE etc
- Created proposals & Refactored systems
- Implemented various features in C# and exposed C APIs to C# for designers
- Added UI code support for various features
- Added Input actions with modifiers & triggers for various features
- Code review for colleagues & helping with estimations
- Wrote plugins for Jetbrains rider for code analysis & quick fixes for in-house libraries usage

Game Programmer | GAMEZOP | INDIA

2021 - 2022

- Developed <u>Pool Master</u>: 8 ball pool multiplayer game for HTML 5
 - Implemented gameplay, client & server
 - Integrated bespoke deterministic physics library
 - Implemented player progression features : Daily rewards & challenges
 - Implemented different game modes : Online, Time Trial & Practice
 - Published the game on Gamezop, Facebook & Snapchat
- Developed <u>Street Dunkies</u>: A roly poly physics based basket ball game
- Collaborated on various casual titles

CONTACT:

Email: ankitsinghkushwah@outlook.com

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/

videogamechef

PORTFOLIO/TECH DEMOS:

ankitsinghkushwah.github.io

EDUCATION:

Simpkins Public School, INDIA

12th class, Scored 74% with Physics, Maths & Chemistry

2013 - 2014

PUBLISHED ARTICLES:

Skeletal Animation with OpenGL

LearnOpenGL dot com | 2020

SKILLS:

Languages: C/C++, C#, Python & Typescript

Graphics APIs : OpenGL & DirectX Game Engine : Unreal 5 & Godot

VCS: Git & Perforce

Performance Analysis: RenderDoc &

Superluminal

SHIPPED GAMES:

Temple Run 2 (>50M plays)
Pool Master (5.5M plays)
Street Dunkies (500k plays)
Bejeweled Blitz (10M Downloads)

PERSONAL PROJECTS HIGHLIGHTS:

Eklavya Engine: C++ game engine with custom rigid body physics, skeletal animation & OpenGL Renderer

CPU Based real time Ray Tracer

Game Programmer on Contract | XANSR TECHNOLOGIES | INDIA

- 4 Months 2020
- Ported Temple Run 2 to HTML 5 for Imangi Studios
 - Implemented character movement, follow camera & animation state machine
 - Simple chase AI state machine when the runner stumbles on obstacles
 - Coin collection mechanic
 - Abilities & Upgrades: Invincible Mode, Water surfing, Coin Magnet & Speed boost
 - Dynamic object placement on procedurally generated tracks
 - Wrote shaders : distanced fog to hide far plane culling & another one for reading baked lighting data
 - Level & graphics optimisations
 - All the VFX are done by me. Because there's no VFX artists

Software Engineer Intern | ELECTRONIC ARTS SLINGSHOT | INDIA

2018 - 2019

- Implemented Spin board for Bejeweled Blitz for both Mobile & HTML 5 (Facebook)
- Added sprite sheet animation to in-house engine
- Updated SDKs for telemetry & Ads
- Did a knowledge sharing session on SIMD
- Bug fixes for different mobile devices
- Peer code reviews